

MAYUR NIKAM

Address: A.p: Undri (SS Platinum Park), Pune 411060

Phone: 9762636082

Email: mayurnikam9696@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mayur-nikam-mraj96/

Versatile Software Developer with 3 years of experience in .Net programming and software engineering. A self-directed leader with expertise in Back-End (.NET Technologies) and database administration (SQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, SQLite). Talented at cultivating a collaborative and supportive team environment.

WORK HISTORY

JUN 2021 TO Present

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, COMMUNITY BRANDS PVT LTD

- Coordinated with consulting team and client's team to evaluate and improve Aptify Product for organizations.
- Collaborated on all stages of the development lifecycle, from requirement gathering to production releases.
- As required worked on JavaScript, front-end, and query optimization as well.
- Got appreciation from the client (ASCM) to optimize the query performance from 15 min to a few seconds and everyone from Consulting team appreciate me for this success.
- Worked with global clients and associations like ASCM (The Association for Supply Chain Management), ONS (Oncology Nursing Society), and APEGA (Association of Professional Engineers and Geoscientists of Alberta).
- Did various applications integration and customization with Aptify, for APEGA clients.
- For ONS client wrote and optimized existing code using LAMBDA, and LINQ and got top votes for this value creation/addition in the company's consulting group.
- Reviewed code, debugged problems, and corrected issues.
- Orchestrated efficient large-scale software deployments, including testing features and correcting code.
- Maintained existing applications and designed and delivered new applications and APIs as and when needed.
- Winner of JavaScript quiz competition.

FEB 2020 TO APR 2021

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, MAXIMOJO SOFTWARE PVT LTD

- Coordinated with Chief Technology Officer (CTO) and Chief Executive Officer (CEO) to evaluate and improve software and hardware interfaces.
- Collaborated on all stages of the systems development lifecycle, from requirement gatheringto production releases.
- Coordinated with project management staff on database development timelines and project scope.
- Worked on Mantras (Product of current organization), Competitor tracking and rate analysis (Product feature), Web Scraping, Web services, Proxy, monitored data, and

- handled database projects using .Net technologies (mainly C#), NoSQL, and OOPS Concepts.
- Prepared test plans and test cases based on Hotel's requirement documents for Mantras Software.
- Monitored and updated back-end data by inter-communicating between Mantras Software and the Front-End layer (UX).
- Administered, supported, and monitored databases by proactively resolving databaseissues and maintaining servers.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitiously, but realistic coding milestoneson pre-release software project development.
- Performed regression and system-level testing to verify software quality and function prior to release.
- Boosted network, system, and data availability and integrity through preventativemaintenance and upgrades.
- Wrote code on the Visual Studio platform using C#, and ASP.Net.
- Handled and managed Database (MongoDB).
- Wrote code on the Spring Framework platform using Java, and J2EE.
- Wrote code on the Eclipse platform using C++.
- Wrote code on the Visual Studio Code platform using Web Technologies like HTML, CSS,Bootstrap, JavaScript, and TypeScript.

EDUCATION

Feb 2019

PG-DAC, Sunbeam Institute of Information Technology, Pune

• Completed Post Graduate Diploma in Advanced Computing (PG-DAC).

MAY 2018

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING, SVPM COE MALEGAON BK (Pune University)

- Completed Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology.
- Graduated with First Class with Distinction.
- Graduated with 66.6 %.
- Elected to General Secretary for Student Organization- ITSA (Information Technology Student Association) for 2017-18.

FEB 2014

П

ı

HSC-SCIENCE, TC COLLEGE, BARAMATI

• Completed HSC from TC College, Baramati in Science stream with a special subject in InformationTechnology.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

• **Project name: Technical Discussion Forum:** Platform: J2EE, Duration: 1 Month (CDAC Academic Project) Project Description: This Project is to be designed for students at an institute to get their doubts clarified by posting their queries. The queries posted by the student are to be resolved by the respective faculties of the institutes. The primary goal is to provide a convenient and efficient environment for the students and the lecturers.

2

Project name: Evaluation from Traditional Farming to Digital Farming: Platform: Android, Java, MySQL, SQLite, Duration: Jul 2018 – Apr 2019 (1 Year: Engineering Project) Project description: Digital Farmer App is an android based application that provides information to farmers regarding different crops and farming practices and other agricultural products. It is dynamic and interactive to take in the feedback and other input from the end users and can guide people regarding the different procedures that need to be adopted. This approach makes a simulation of a live environment that takes different aspects into consideration like market demand and supply, production forecast, fertilizer preferences, etc. It stores all expenses required for the farm and costs for the worker and finds the details of the market rate for different nearby markets.

SKILLS

- Net development
 - C#
 - Java and J2EE
 - SQL and No-SQL Database
 - Problem-solving.

- Web Technologies
- Hardware and software installation
- Quality Assurance Testing
- OOPS concepts
- Computer programming and coding

CERTIFICATIONS

Name: CDAC (Centre for Development of Advanced Computing)
URL:

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1tpS H3pGYJb fuMGdX3o0W4VJIwbyV2E/view?usp=sharing

• Name: SQL Training (From Simplilearn)

URL:

https://certificates.simplicdn.net/share/3134730.pdf

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

• Volunteer (as the Main Coordinator of the IT Department) at CRETECHNOVA 2018 technical events at SVPM COE MALEGAON.

PUBLICATIONS

- Title: Evaluation from Traditional Farming to Digital Farming.
- **Publication/Publisher:** International Research Journal of Engineering and Technology (IRJET).
 - Publication URL: https://www.irjet.net/archives/V5/i3/IRJET-V5I3547.pdf

ACKNOWLEDGMENT

I hereby declare that the information given above is true to the best of my Information knowledge belief.

Date:	Signature: Mayur Balasaheb Nikam